gaastraproshop.com 2018-09-03

# Privacy statement

_Effective date: April 2018_

Gaastra Mode B.V. with its corporate office located [Amsterdamseweg 206, 1182 HL Amstelveen, The Netherlands] and our affiliated businesses (collectively, " **Gaastra** " or " **us** ") are committed to being responsible custodians of the information you provide us and the information we collect in the course of operating our business. 

Gaastra takes your personal privacy seriously. This Privacy Statement describes how Gaastra, as a data controller, collects, uses and shares information, particularly in association with the operation of our website www.gaastrastore.com and our other websites, and the provision of our products and services. This Privacy Statement applies to all personal data collected by Gaastra from individuals in the European Union. 

This Privacy Statement describes:

·       The types of information Gaastra collects

·       How Gaastra uses the information Gaastra collects

·       How Gaastra may share the information Gaastra collects

·       Third-Party services and content

·       Protection and storage of the information Gaastra collects

·       Your choices and rights

·       Changes to this Privacy Statement

·       Use of Cookies

## The types of information Gaastra collects

Gaastra collects your personal data when you provide it to us, for instance by visiting our website, contacting our customer service or by purchasing products through our web shop. " **Personal data** " is any information that can be used to identify you or that Gaastra can link to you, for instance your name and email address.

All personal data you provide to us or that we (automatically) collect is voluntarily. However, without providing certain data, for instance your email address, we may not be able to respond to your request or deliver our services.

_Your account_

Gaastra collects the following information when you sign up for an account on our website: name, email address, gender, date of birth and postal address. 

_Use of our products and services_

When you use our products and services we will ask for personal data (at the moment of collection we will explain what information is required in order for us to provide the particular product or service, and what information you may choose to provide). For example, Gaastra collects the following information when you use our web shop: your name, email address, gender, date of birth, postal address and payment information. We also keep a record of our correspondence with you (including any feedback you have provided on any of our products or services), if you have been in contact with our customer service.

_Information we collect automatically_

We use browser cookies and similar technologies to collect and store certain information when you use, access, or interact with us via our websites. We collect information such as your IP address, the date and time of the visit and how long you remained on our website, the referral URL (the site from which the visitor has come), the pages visited on our website and information about the device and browser (such as, browser type and version and operating system). Click here for more information about our use of cookies and how to disable them.

_Information we collect from other sources_

Gaastra may also collect information from other sources, such as social media platforms that may share information about how you interact with our social media content, or if you interact with us via our social media accounts.

_Information of children_

Our website and services are generally not directed to children under 16. Gaastra does not knowingly collect personal data from anyone under 16 without parental consent. If you become aware that Gaastra has collected personal data from a child under the age of 16 without parental consent, please let us know so Gaastra can take appropriate action.

## How Gaastra uses the information Gaastra collects

Gaastra will only process personal data where it has a legal basis to do so. Gaastra may use the information Gaastra collects:

(a)            To enter into a contract or settlement, or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract or settlement (such as account registration);

(b)            To process your order: we use relevant personal data described above (including your name, address and payment details) to process and deliver your order, and to notify you of the status of your order. In addition, we may use your age, year of birth or confirmation that you are above a certain age to ascertain whether you meet the minimum age in your country for online purchases and whether you are considered to be a minor for data protection and/or marketing law purposes. It is necessary to process your personal data in this way for the performance of the contract we have with you;

(c)            To respond to your inquiries and provide you with customer support services, to communicate with third parties in the handling of claims or complaints, to maintain business administration records and prevent fraud, which is our legitimate business interest to properly provide our services to you;

(d)            To keep records and administration on how products and services were provided, claims and complaints were handled, including the documents underlying such services, claims and complaints, which is our legitimate business interest to maintain proper administration of disputes;

(e)            To understand how people use our website and services, to learn more about our customers and their preferences, to operate, maintain and improve our website and services, to develop new products and services, to send direct marketing communications, which is our legitimate business interest to improve your customer experience with us; 

(f)             To comply with legal obligations applicable to Gaastra, such as respond to legal process or requests for information issued by government authorities or other third parties or to protect your, our or other parties' rights.

Your personal data may be transferred to and stored in countries outside the European Economic Area at a server of Gaastra in compliance with the European General Data Protection Regulation. If you have questions about the appropriate safeguards Gaastra has in place or wish to obtain a copy of such safeguards, please see below under "How Gaastra may share the information Gaastra collects" and/or contact us via [service@gaastra-group.com].

## How Gaastra may share the information Gaastra collects

Gaastra and its affiliated entities share information with each other or with third-party service providers for general business purposes and analytical purposes pursued by Gaastra, such as internal administration, billing, claim handling and services, and providing you or your organization with services.

Gaastra and its affiliated entities may share information with third-party data controllers (including law enforcement agencies and potential transaction partners) where Gaastra and its affiliated entities have a legal basis to do so. 

Gaastra does not sell, rent, or otherwise share personal data with information that reasonably identifies you for their independent use except as expressly described in this Privacy Statement or when Gaastra has a legal basis to do so, for instance with your prior consent.

If Gaastra transfers your personal data to a recipient outside the European Union, it will only do so in compliance with the European General Data Protection Regulation. In these circumstances we will take appropriate steps to ensure that your personal data is adequately protected. Typically, such steps include carrying out data security reviews of any recipients and putting in place contracts with such recipients to ensure they employ the same or similar appropriate technical and organisational measures as Gaastra, so your data is adequately protected. For more information on the international transfers of your personal data or the appropriate safeguards in place, please contact us via [service@gaastra-group.com].

## Third-party services and content

Our website may include integrated content or links to content provided by third parties (such as social media platforms). This Privacy Statement does not address the privacy, security, or other practices of the third parties that provide such content. We recommend considering the privacy statements applicable to third-party websites prior to visiting those websites. Gaastra is not responsible for the way in which these third parties handle your personal data. 

Gaastra engages third parties that support the operation of our website, such as analytics providers. These third parties may use technologies to track your online activities over time and across different websites and online platforms. Please click here for more information.

## Protection and storage of the information Gaastra collects 

Gaastra is committed to protecting your personal data and we implement appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to safeguard the information that Gaastra collects. However, no information system can be 100% secure. This means that Gaastra cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personal data. Moreover, Gaastra is not responsible for the security of information you transmit to us over networks that Gaastra does not control, including the internet and wireless networks.

Gaastra retains the information collected in an identifiable form as long as reasonably necessary and only for as long as required to fulfill the purposes and on the lawful grounds described above for which Gaastra collects the information and to comply with our legal obligations. This means that we will keep your personal data as long as necessary to be able to provide you with our products and services and to be able to respond to your requests. 

The following are examples to illustrate how Gaastra keeps your personal data for as long as necessary for a particular purpose:

§  we may keep your personal data collected during a purchase for as long as required by national tax laws (longer than 2 years in some European countries);

§  we may keep the personal data in your online account for 2 years after the date you deleted your account;

§  we delete your email address used for direct marketing purposes (such as newsletters) after you have informed us that you do not want to receive any such communications from us anymore.

## Your choices and rights

Fair play and transparency are important to us. We are open about the personal data we collect and have implemented mechanisms to enable you to exercise any rights you might have with respect to your personal data. 

We encourage you to contact us to update or correct your information if it changes or if you believe that any information that we have collected about you is inaccurate. You can also ask us to see what personal data we hold about you, to rectify or erase your personal data, or to port your personal data and you may tell us if you object to or want to restrict our use of your personal data. 

Where we process your personal data on the basis of your consent (e.g. your consent to receiving direct marketing messages or your consent to the placement of cookies on your device), you may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at the address below. If you would like to opt out of receiving direct marketing communications, you can also use the unsubscribe link contained in the message you have received. Where we process your personal data on the basis of our or a third party's legitimate interest, you may object to such processing at any time by contacting us at the address below.

If you would like to discuss or exercise your rights, please contact us via [service@gaastra-group.com]. You can also use this address to lodge a complaint. If you are not satisfied about the manner in which Gaastra handles your complaint, you may also lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority.

For information about the choices you may have in regard to our use of cookies, please click here.

## Use of Cookies

Gaastra collects certain information by automated means when you visit our website. By collecting this information, Gaastra learns how to best tailor our website to our visitors. Gaastra collects this information through various means such as “cookies,” “web beacons”, and “IP addresses” as explained below.

More information about the cookies we use on our website is set out [here].

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

Gaastra may update this Privacy Statement from time to time to keep it up to date, to keep pace with new developments and opportunities relating to the internet and to stay in line with applicable law. The effective date of the current Privacy Statement is noted at the top of this page. Gaastra encourages you to periodically review this page. You will be informed separately if we make changes to this Privacy Statement which may have a significant impact on your private life.
